Nikos Gereoudakis

gereoudakis@gmail.com | github | linkedin | twitter | stackoverflow

Athens, Greece, Last updated: 14 February 2022

Summary

I am an experienced software engineer with experience in UI and API development and expertise in Typescript and the broader Javascript ecosystem.

I enjoy working on different parts of the web stack (front and back end development, DevOps and UX) and I care deeply about software quality, maintenance and performance, development processes, teamwork and collaboration.

When the occasion arises I'm happy to step up in a leadership role and help on improving processes, improving team happiness, planning and prioritization.

Work experience

SEP 2020

Senior software engineer / Tech lead (remote) @ theoremone.co

Dec 2021

This is the same consultancy with one of my previous entries named <u>citrusbyte.com</u>, they <u>re-branded</u> recently. They've contacted me last summer and I joined in September. The programme I joined (<u>BSI's new shop</u>) had started in May.

Co-led a small team together with the Product Manager and Engineering manager. Participated in planning, prioritization, design reviews and worked in a few different roles: Senior Full-Stack Engineer, Lead Full-Stack Engineer, Tech Lead.

Worked mostly in a Next.js application (React/Typescript) and a separate "middleware" backend app (nodejs/Typescript/koa) that was handling authentication and authorization in front of several C#/dotnet microservices. All the services were deployed in a kubernetes cluster in Azure.

Worked on configuring multiple environments (dev/qa/uat/production), monitoring, alerting and CI/CD.

Utilized several SaaS such as Contentful, Algolia and Shopify and implemented migration scripts for the deployment pipeline.

Worked on a few Ruby scripts for Shopify Scripts and also built a custom Shopify App in React for administrative purposes

<u>Technologies used</u>: Typescript, Next.js, React, koa.js, GraphQL/Apollo, Jest, TestCafe, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, Terraform.

May 2019

Senior software engineer (remote) @ scribd.com

JULY 2020

Worked as a member of the Web team on the Ruby on Rails monolith and a few Single Page Applications.

I worked as part of the product team in new features and A/B tests but also in more infrastructure work such as monitoring, alerting and CI/CD.

Participated in an ad-hoc "Monolith migration" team who was responsible for the migration of the Rails application, its datastores and metrics/alerts to the cloud (Amazon Web Services, Datadog). This migration lasted around 6 months and included the implementation of double writes to both data centers with endpoint optimisation when needed, the addition of a ProxySQL service for SQL query routing, gradual traffic switch via Fastly VCL rules, migration of Grafana dashboards to Datadog and more.

<u>Technologies used</u>: Typescript, React (including SSR with hypernova), Redux, Jest, WebdriverlO, SCSS, webpack, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Terraform, Chef, nagios, Gitlab, Jenkins, Grafana, Datadog, Databricks, ProxySQL, Fastly.

Jul 2017

Lead front-end engineer (remote) @ datatiger.com

DEC 2018

Worked as the first and only developer of the front-end stack of datatiger.com. The company was about event-triggered marketing and was acquired by $\underline{\mathsf{Apple}}$ on December. I didn't continue working for the new owner due to a relocation requirement.

Architected and developed a Single Page App which could also be used as independent components based on React.

Implemented (in React) and contributed to a design system.

Configured and maintained all application environments (staging, production, CI) and deployment strategies.

Participated in REST API Design.

Participated in User Experience Design.

Kept test coverage above 90% at all times.

Technologies used: React, Redux, Jest, D3, fela (CSS-in-JS), draft.js, webpack, AWS, Docker.

Nov 2014

Senior front-end engineer (remote) @ citrusbyte.com

Jun 2017

■ Lead front-end engineer on AT&T IoT Platform Team [Nov 2014 - Jun 2017].

Closely collaborated with the Product, API and Design/UX teams.

Led a small team (2-4) of front end engineers.

Contributed to the partial rewrite of $\underline{M2X}$ from Backbone to React and continued working as lead developer until Mar 2016.

Developed embedable Javascript widgets for the M2X platform.

Contributed to the development of AT&T IoT Marketplace.

Bootstrapped a new IoT project named "AT&T Pipelines" which eventually became AT&T Dataflow.

and led the effort for the creation of a reusable UI library across all projects.

<u>Technologies used</u>: React, Redux, Redux Saga, Backbone, D3, LESS, SCSS, webpack, mocha, chai, sinon, karma, phantom, nightwatch, Ruby, Cuba.rb, Redis, ElasticSearch, PostgreSQL, Docker, RabbitMQ.

Senior front-end engineer on <u>Asset 360</u> [Mar 2016 - Jun 2016].

Contributed in the design and implementation of an asset tracking prototype for Infor/Caterpillar. The back end API that was developed for this prototype makes heavy use of the AT&T M2X API.

<u>Technologies used</u>: React, Redux, immutable.js, reselect, Less, webpack, mocha, chai, sinon, karma, phantomJS.

Mar 2013

Lead front-end engineer @ holic.com (not available any more)

APRIL 2014

Worked as the lead developer of the front-end stack of holic.com.

Architected and contributed to the development of a Single Page App based on Backbone/Marionette.js.

Contributed to the development of an express.js REST API that wraps the ZMQ backend API and provides some extra services on top of that.

Configured and maintained all application environments and deployment strategies.

Participated in User Experience and Funnel Optimization.

Technologies used: Marionette.js, Jasmine, express.js, Mocha, socket.io, Redis, Grunt, requirejs, SASS, Git, nginx.

Sep 2012

Freelance software engineer

Mar 2013

Front/back end work for various clients/agencies. Mainly in Ruby/Javascript.

Feb 2012

Software engineer / Owner @ hotelkeeper.gr (not available any more)

Aug 2012

Designed and developed a Content Management System for the accommodation industry. This was a small business experiment which I executed alone. I terminated the service at the end of 2016 since I managed to acquire only ~20 customers.

<u>Technologies used</u>: Ruby on Rails, Backbone.js, RequireJS, RSpec, Capybara, Jasmine, MySQL, jQuery, jQuery Mobile, Coffeescript, SASS, Twitter bootstrap, Amazon S3/Cloudfront, Git, nginx, Passenger.

May 2011

Software engineer @ skroutz.gr

Jan 2012

Participated in a big refactor in order to improve performance and test coverage.

Implemented OAuth2 Server and UI for Skroutz Easy.

Created new tools for the content team to ease categorization of new products.

Implemented a modular classifier for automatic categorization and grouping of new products using heuristics and clustering.

	Technologies used: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, Capybara, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Sphinx, Memcached, jQuery, Coffeescript, SASS, Git.
Sep 2010	Software engineer (part time contract, remote) @ artavita.com
- Feв 2011	Developed a web app for visual artists' portfolios and contests based on a given design.
	<u>Technologies used</u> : Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Ubuntu, Apache/Passenger, ActiveMerchant, Paypal, jQuery and Git.
Apr 2009	Senior Software Engineer @ <u>zulutrade.com</u>
Mar 2011	Worked as the lead developer of the Trading API of Zulutrade which is responsible for all auto-trading and is written in Java.
	Designed and developed many features of the service from database modeling to Java implementation.
	Refactored existing codebase to improve performance and maintainability.
	Participated in various DBA tasks that required knowledge of the business model.
	<u>Technologies used</u> : Java SE/EE, Python, SVN, MySQL, JMS, HornetQ, XML/RPC various APIs.
Ост 2008	Software engineer @ evtch.tech (outsourcing company)
_ Mar 2009	I was outsourced as a Java web developer for the development team of a telecommunications provider (Ontelecoms - probably acquired by Vodafone) for their CRM and WebSelfCare websites.
	<u>Technologies used</u> : Java, JSP, Struts, Hibernate, EJB, JBoss, SOAP (Axis), JDeveloper, Javascript, jQuery, Oracle 9, Sourcesafe.

Implemented the integration of Skroutz Merchants with DIAS payment system.

EDUCATION

2006–2007	M.Sc. in Signal Processing (Distinction) University of Bristol, UK
2000–2006	B.Sc. in Physics (7.14/10)
	Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, Greece